Joseph Stephen Cullinan Collection, 1895-1939
University of Houston Libraries
Joseph Stephen Cullinan Collection, 1895-1939
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Cullinan, J. S. (Joseph Stephen), 1860-1937
69 Boxes
Joseph Stephen Cullinan founded the Texas Company and was a key figure in the commerical and cultural history of Houston in the early 20th century. This collection contains correspondence, records and other materials relating to Cullinan's business ventures, family life, and community involvement.
2006-009
Biographical Note
Few of the major figures in the history of Houston have had as widespread an influence as Joseph Stephen Cullinan. At times, the word paradoxical comes to mind when the scope of his diverse interests is examined. A leading early exponent for the Texas oil industry, Cullinan was yet an ardent conservationist, who argued for governmental controls over the petroleum business out of concern for preserving natural resources. Although he maintained a fairly consistent record of lifetime support for the Democratic Party, Cullinan advocated the Progressive candidacy of Robert LaFollette in 1924 and in the later years of his life supported the reactionary Liberty League after he became disenchanted with the policies of the New Deal. Despite his flirtations with nativist movements, he strongly opposed the Ku Klux Klan as a result of his own Irish Catholic background, even though he disavowed any affiliation with organized religion.
Arriving in Corsicana, Texas from his native Pennsylvania, where he was born on December 31, 1860, Cullinan immediately became involved in the exploration and drilling of the Corsicana oil fields, borrowing on his own experiences as an oil field worker for Standard Oil. After the discoveries at Spindletop in 1901 shifted the geographical emphasis of the Texas oil industry to the Beaumont area, Cullinan moved his own center of operations there, where he became president of the newly-formed Texas Company in 1902. Recognizing the potential of Houston as an oil center, Cullinan moved the headquarters of the Texas Company there in 1908.
Scope and Contents
Aside from its obvious use as a significant source for those persons interested in the petroleum industry, this collection covers a wide range of other research topics. Business and economic historians will be interested in the extensive financial records and correspondence of such companies as the Petroleum Iron Works Co., Producers Oil Co., the Texas Company, Farmer's Petroleum Co., and the American Republics Corporation. The collection includes records of the land division of the Shadyside subdivision, accounts of the construction of Cullinan's Shadyside residence and of the building and maintenance of his Pasadena farm. These particular documents provide a wealth of information for architectural and agricultural historians. Finally, historians of the City of Houston will be able to make use of the records of Cullinan's integral involvement with the improvement of the city through such efforts as the Houston Negro Hospital, the Northside Belt Railway, and the founding of the Museum of Fine Arts. Political scientists will find his participation in politics on the local, state, and national level as well as his involvement in Irish affairs and other international issue of particular interest.
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Magnolia Petroleum Company; Museum of Fine Arts, Houston; Petroleum Iron Works Company of Texas; Texas Company
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence; Records
Geographic Name:
Shadyside (Houston, Tex.)
Personal Name:
Autry, James L.; Cullinan, J. S. (Joseph Stephen), 1860-1937
Topical Term:
Petroleum industry and trade--Texas; Texas Centennial (1936: Dallas, Tex.); Texas Centennial (1936: San Jacinto Battleground, Tex.)
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Detailed Description
- Box List
  - The Texas Company Private Letters, J.S. Cullinan, President (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Texas Company Private Letters, J.S. Cullinan, President (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Texas Company Private Letters, J.S. Cullinan, President (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Texas Company, W.L. Holmes, February 17, 1905 to April 1905 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Private Letters, February 1, 1902 to April 20, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - J.S. Cullinan Private, June 1, 1903 to September 1, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - J.S. Cullinan Private, September 1, 1903 to December 29, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - J.S. Cullinan Private Letters, December 29, 1903 to March 9, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - J.S. Cullinan Private Letters, March 9, 1904 to May 24, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - J.S. Cullinan Private Letters, May 25, 1904 to November 17, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - J.S. Cullinan Private Letters, November 18, 1904 to February 25, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - J.S. Cullinan Private Letters, February 27, 1904 to April 12, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - J.S. Cullinan Private Letters to Arnold Schlaet, October 1, 1902 to July 24, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - J.S. Cullinan Private Letters to Arnold Schlaet, July 29, 1903 to August 16, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - J.S. Cullinan Private Letters to Arnold Schlaet, September 17, 1904 to April 1, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - J.S.C. Personal Beaumont Letters (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - J.S.C. Personal (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - J.S. Cullinan Letters to Employees, November 15, 1904 to April 1, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1895 - 1901 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Concerning the Acme Coment Plaoler Company, 1898-1900 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, A-F, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, G-M, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Mckie and Autry, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, M-S, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Garva, E. Strong, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, T-Z, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, A-B, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, George M. Brows, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, C-E, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Citizens National Bank, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, F-I, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Harris, Gates, and Company, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, J-N, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Mckie and Autry, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, O-S, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence, T-Z, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - General Correspondence, A-C, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, E.R. Brown, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, W.T. Campbell, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - General Correspondence, D-G, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - General Correspondence, H-J, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - General Correspondence, K-L, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - General Correspondence, M-N, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, Mckie and Autry, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - General Correspondence, O-P, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - General Correspondence, Q-S, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, Arnold Schlaet, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, Garva E. Strong, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, T-Z, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, A-B, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, C, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, W.T. Campbell, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, D-E, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, F, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Fred, W. Freeman, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, G, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Charles G. and John W. Gales, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, H-J, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, K-N, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Cal. E. Kerr, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Concerning Landslide Oil Company, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Mckie and Autry, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, N-P, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, G. Neely, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Petroleum Iron Works - A.W. Krouse, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Petroleum Iron Works - C.J. McDowell, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, W.C. Proctor, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, Q-T, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, Arnold Schlaet, Jan. 1-23, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, Arnold Schlaet, Jan. 23-Dec. 31, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, U-Z, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - General Correspondence, A-B, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, W.M. Abbey and Co., 1906 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, William D. Bates, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, E.R. Brown, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - General Correspondence, C, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, W.T. Campbell, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cullinan Family Correspondence, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, D-F, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, G, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Charles G. and John Gates, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, H, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Concerning Horses, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, I-J, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Cal E. Kerr, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, K-L, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, M, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, N-O, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, P, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, Petroleum Iron Works Co., 1906 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Petroleum Iron Works - Correspondence Concerning move to Sharvn, Pa., 1906 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Concerning Producers Oil Co., 1906 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, Q-R, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - General Financial Accounts, Petroleum Iron Works Co., 1890's (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Financial Accounts - Miscellaneous, 1905-1914 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Financial Accounts - Great Southern Life Insurance Co., 1912-1913 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Financial Accounts; Production Reports, Central Petroleum Co., 1913 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Financial Accounts - Monthly Analysis Sheets, 1914-1915 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Trust Company Financial Accounts, 1914-1915 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - General Correspondence, S, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence Concerning J.P. Smith Co., 1906 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - General Correspondence, T-Z, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence Concerning Texas Company Stock, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - General Correspondence, A-B, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - General Correspondence, C, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Cullinan Family Correspondence, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - General Correspondence, D-F, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, G-H, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, J.W. Gates, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, W.L. Holmes, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Houston Residence File, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, I-L, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Cal E. Kerr, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, M, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, N-P, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Petroleum Iron Works Co., 1907 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, O-S, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, T-Z, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Concerning Taxes, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Concerning Texas Co. Stock, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Concerning Union Bank and Trust Company, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence, A-B, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, C, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Cullinan Family Correspondence, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - General Correspondence, D-G, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence Concerning Debentures, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence Concerning Farm Property, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - General Correspondence, H-K, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, Cal E. Kerr, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - General Correspondence, L-M, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, C.J. McDowell, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - General Correspondence, N-R, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, G. Neely, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - General Correspondence, S-T, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence Concerning Taxes, 1908 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Concerning Texas Company Stock, 1908 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, U-Z, 1908 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, A-B, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Concerning Boat Launch, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, C, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Cullinan Family Correspondence, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, D-E, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Concerning Debentures, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, F-G, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Concerning Farm, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, John W. Gates, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, H, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Harris, Winthrop, and Co., 1909 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Cal E. Kerr, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence, I-K, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, L, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence, M, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - General Correspondence, N, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - General Correspondence, O-P, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - General Correspondence, Q-S, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - General Correspondence, T-V, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence Concerning Taxes, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence Concerning Texas Co. Stock, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - General Correspondence, W-Z, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - General Correspondence, A, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - General Correspondence, B-C, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Cullinan Family Correspondence, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, V.R. Currie, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - General Correspondence, D-G, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, Debentures, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence Concerning Farm Property, Jan.-May 1910 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence Concerning Farm Property, June - Dec. 1910 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, H-K, 1910 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Harris, Winthrop, and Co., 1910 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Cal E. Kerr, 1910 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, L-M, 1910 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, N-R, 1910 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Producers Oil Company, 1910 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, S, 1910 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, T-V, 1910 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, W-Y, 1910 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, A-Z, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Concerning Craig and John H. Cullinan, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Concerning Cal E. Kerr, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Concerning Taxes, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, A-B, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, James L. Autry, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, C, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Concerning Car - Accident, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence Concerning Car - Miscellaneous, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence Concerning Hiring of Chauffeur, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Cullinan Family Correspondence, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, V.R. Currie, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - General Correspondence, D, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - General Correspondence, E, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - General Correspondence, F-G, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence Concerning Farm, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, Charles G. Gates, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, Great Southern Life Insurance Co., 1912 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - General Correspondence, H, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - General Correspondence, I-K, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, Cal E. Kerr, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - General Correspondence, L-M, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - General Correspondence, N-O, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - General Correspondence, P-R, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence Concerning Pawling School, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, Petroleum Iron Works Co., 1912 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence, Producers Oil Company, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, Richland Quarry Company, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - General Correspondence, S, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Concerning Securities, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Concerning Walter and Sharp, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Concerning Southern Trust Company, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, T, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Concerning Taxes, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, U-Z, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Concerning Wolters Club, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Architectural Drawings - Miscellaneous, 1902-1913 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Maps - Miscellaneous Texas, 1902-1914 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Maps - Miscellaneous Non-Texas, 1902-1915 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, A-B, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Luther Burbank Society, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, C, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, R.B. Caldwell, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Concerning City Plan for Houston, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Concerning Car, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Cullinan Family Correspondence, Jan. - July, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Cullinan Family Correspondence, Aug. - Dec. 1913 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, V.R. Currie, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - General Correspondence, D-E, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence Concerning Employed Compensation Act, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, Equitable Trust Company, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - General Correspondence, F, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence Concerning Farm Property, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - General Correspondence, G, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, Charles G. Gates, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence Concerning Goss Family Property, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - General Correspondence, H, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, Will C. Hogg, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - General Correspondence, I-J, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence Concerning Insurance, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - General Correspondence, K-L, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, Cal E. Kerr, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - General Correspondence, M, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, W.L. Murphy, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, N-R, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Concerning Pawling School, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Petroleum Iron Works Co., 1913 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Producers Oil Co., Mexican Properties, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Producers Oil Co.- Miscellaneous, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Raywood Canal and Milling Co., 1913 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Concerning Resignation, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Richard Quarry Co., 1913 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, S, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Securities, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Estate of Walter B. Sharp and Sharp-Hughes Tool Co., 1913 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, T, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Texas Commercial Secretaries and Businessmen's Association, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Concerning Texas Industrial Congress, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Trinity Engineering and Construction Co., 1913 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence, U-Z, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence Concerning Wheeler Oil Filed, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - General Correspondence, A-Z, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, Chemical National Bank, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Cullinan Family Correspondence, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, W.H. Gray, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence Concerning Securities, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, Sharp-Hughes Tool Co. (Hughes Drill), 1914 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, Texas Employers Insurance Association, Jan. - May, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, Texas Employers Insurance Association, June - Dec., 1914 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, U.S. Government, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - General Correspondence, A-Z, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, Chemical National Bank, January - May, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, Chemical National Bank, June - Dec., 1915 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Denver Account, 1915 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, W.H. Gray, 1915 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, A-Z, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Chemical National Bank, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, A-Z, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Chemical National Bank, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Securities, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, A-Z, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Chemical National Bank, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, E.E. Morrison, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, A-Z, 1919 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Chemical National Bank, 1919 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, E.E. Morrison,1919 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, A-Z, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Chemical National Bank, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Chemical National Bank, 1921 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Chemical National Bank, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Personal Correspondence: Mrs. James L. Autry, 1924-1925 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Personal Correspondence: Mrs. James L. Autry, 1926-1929 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Personal Correspondence: Mrs. James L. Autry, 1930-1935 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Personal Correspondence: Autry House, 1921-1928 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Personal Correspondence: Jonathan Bourne, 1932-1933 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Personal Correspondence: Autry Memorial Hospital School, 1922-1926 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Personal Correspondence: Autry Memorial Hospital School, 1927-1934 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Personal Correspondence: Autry Memorial Hospital School Records, 1926-1929 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Personal Correspondence: Autry Memorial Hospital School Records, 1930-1934 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Personal Correspondence: Autry Memorial Hospital School Records, 1935-1936 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Personal Correspondence: Autry Estate, Audit Reports, 1926-1936 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Personal Correspondence: Gutzon Borglum (Mount Rushmore), 1928-1936 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Personal Correspondence: Nicholas Murry Butler, 1925-1932 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence: Richard Campbell, 1925-1927 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Personal Correspondence: Richard Campbell, 1928-1930 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Personal Correspondence: Richard Campbell, 1931-1932 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Personal Correspondence: Richard Campbell, 1933-1934 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Personal Correspondence: Richard Campbell, 1935-1936 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Personal Correspondence: E.A. Frost, 1921-1926 (Box 12, Folder 8)